My grandmother was the queen mother
when when she died my elder sister took over,
and then when she died I was made the Queen Mother
In the Asante Kingdom, when someone rapes a
child or a family member,
he is banished from the village,
This is because the person has brought a curse on
the village,
so the person is driven out.
Then the village performs certain rituals to take the
curse out of the land.
Anything on this land, be it palm tree, or sand -
because in this town we have sand for construction
and building purposes -
therefore when we sell these resources from the land,
whatever the people need, we provide it
from the proceeds.
Some was used to build toilet facilities, electricity,
wells for water
and also with the introduction of formal education we
built primary schools for our people.