My name is Nana Yaa Adomaa.
My stool name is Adomakoa Atookuafuo, the king's
wife Adomakoa Atookuafuo
I}n this town, the stool belongs to the wife of the Asante King.
The Asante King gave this land to his wife who lived
with the Atookwa people.
Because there is no male leader in this town, I the
King's wife am in charge of this town.
When there is a conflict between two parties, the
matter is presented before me.
I sit in council with my Elders and brainstorm
about it in order to bring peace.
We hear both parties and based on our findings the
one who is at fault is made to apologize
and the one who has been offended is asked to be
patient with the other
so that we can all live peacefully
When someone needs anything, they come to me
and when I am in need of anything, I also ask
I live peacefully with everyone.
My town folks see me as the King's wife with a
high-level of knowledge.
When there is a situation that calls for my advice or
a problem I need to solve, my Elders present
the matter to me and I preside over it.
That is how we rule in this town.
Everyone is welcome at any time to visit me.